Washington Apple Pi collection of Apple user group newsletters and publications M1087
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Washington Apple Pi collection of Apple user group newsletters and publications
1977-1999
M1087
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Washington Apple Pi (Group)
32.2 Linear Feet 33 boxes
Washington Apple Pi is a non-profit Apple user group in Washington, D.C., and has published a newsletter since 1979. This collection contains most issues from 1980 to 1999. Washington Apple Pi also exchanged newsletters with many other user groups, and these constitute the majority of the collection.
History
Washington Apple Pi [http://www.wap.org] is a non-profit Apple user group which was founded in 1978 in Washington, D.C., and has published a newsletter since 1979. This collection contains most issues of their newsletter from 1980 to 1999. Washington Apple Pi also traded newsletters with many other Apple user groups in an informal exchange program, and these issues constitute the majority of the collection. These computer clubs were for the most part small, regional, and unaffiliated with Apple Computers. Their publications are by-and-large self-produced, and one may observe the birth and development of desktop publishing in their efforts throughout the 1980s and 90s. Computer culture, and more specifically Apple user culture, abounds in these pages. Industry news and gossip, humor, and anti-Microsoft sentiments are published alongside announcements, reviews, and tutorials. Many debate issues such as the ethics of sharing software (which was one of the reasons many of these groups were formed). Any history of Apple's impact on consumers should include these publications.
Scope & Contents
This collection has been arranged and described in alphabetical order by serial title. Each publication is listed by title, group, and location. References are used to connect related publications and name changes. There are few complete runs of issues for any group, and single issues were gathered under "miscellaneous newsletters."
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by Washington Apple Pi to Stanford University, Special Collections in August 1999.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Science -- History.; Apple Computer, Inc.; Computer industry.; Newsletters; Washington Apple Pi (Group)
- II Alive (Scantron Quality Computers), 1996 (Box 1)
- The Abacus II (Apple Bay Area Computer Users Society), 1980-1982 (Box 1)
- Active Window (Boston Computer Society Macintosh User Group, Massachusetts), 1984-1990 (Box 1)
- Adam's Apple (Arizona Desert Apple Menagerie II) [see AZ Apple], 1985-1986 (Box 1)
- Alert! Media Map Alert, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
- AMUG News (Arizona Macintosh User Group), 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Annie's Letter (Fukuoka, Japan), 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- APCU Newsletter / Journal of the APCU (Association of Personal Computer Users), 1980-1982 (Box 1)
- APL/AUG Newsletter (Applied Physics Laboratory Apple Computer User Group, Johns Hopkins University, Columbia, Maryland), 1982 (Box 1)
- Apple2000 (National Apple User Group), 1986-1992 (Box 2)
- Apple Access (Louisville Apple User Group, Kentucky), 1987-1989 (Box 2)
- Apple Assembly Line (S-C Software, Richardson, Texas), 1980-1988 (Box 2)
- The Apple Barrel (Ridgecrest Apple User Group, California), 1985-1995 (Box 2)
- Apple Barrel (Houston Area Apple User Group, Texas), 1981-1998 (Box 2, Box 3)
- Apple Bits / NEO Apple Bits (NEO Apple Corp, Cleveland, Ohio), 1983-1995 (Box 3)
- Apple Byte (Club Apple User Group, Charleston, West Virginia), 1989-1994 (Box 4)
- Apple Bytes (Apple Corp of Memphis, Tennessee), 1989-1998 (Box 4)
- Apple Cookbook (Apple Orchard, Vacaville, California), 1980 (Box 4)
- Apple-Dayton Journal (Ohio), 1981-1994 (Box 5, Box 4)
- Apple-Dillo (River City Apple Corp, Austin, Texas), 1980-1990 (Box 5)
- Apple Jack (Apple Jacks- Jersey Amateur Computer Klub, New Jersey), 1983-1988 (Box 5)
- Apple Library User Group Newsletter (ALUG), 1989, 1993 (Box 5)
- Apple Peel (Birmingham Apple User Group, Alabama) [see The Peel], 1982-1989 (Box 5)
- Apple Pickers (Central Indiana Association of Microcomputer Users), 1981-1998 (Box 5, Box 6)
- Apple Pulp / The Pulp (Hartford User Group Exchange, Connecticut), 1983-1998 (Box 6)
- Apple Sac News (Apple Users Group of Sacramento, California), 1985-1990 (Box 6)
- Apple S.L.I.C.E. (Salt Lake Intermountain Computer Enthusiasts), 1981-1989 (Box 6)
- The Apple Spice Newsletter (Delaware Valley Apple Club for the G.S.), 1991-1996 (Box 6)
- Apple Three News + Views (A3 Group International), 1985-1987 (Box 6)
- Apple Three Users of Northern California, 1985-1991 (Box 7)
- The Apple Tree (Appleshare, Connecticut), 1987-1994 (Box 7)
- The Apple Tree (Syracuse Apple Users Group, New York), 1983-1998 (Box 7)
- Apple Users News + Views (Apple User Groups International) [see Apple Three News + Views], 1987-1991 (Box 7)
- Apple-Works Forum (National Appleworks Users Group), 1986-1995 (Box 7, Box 8)
- Applecations (Apple User Group Sydney Australia), 1981-1990 (Box 8)
- The Applegram / The Michigan AppleGram (Michigan Apple Computer Club), 1981-1998 (Box 9, Box 8)
- Appleholics Anonymous (Ventura, California), 1988-1995 (Box 9)
- Apples B.C. News (Apples British Colombia Computer Society, Burnaby, B.C., Canada), 1985-1994 (Box 9)
- Atlanta Macintosh Users Group Newsletter (AMUG), 1992-1993 (Box 9)
- Autograph (Automated Graphic Systems), 1995-1996 (Box 9)
- AZ Apple (Arizona Apple Users Group) [see Adam's Apple], 1986-1992 (Box 9)
- Big Apple Users Digest / BAUD (Big Apple Users Group, New York), 1981-1990 (Box 9)
- BCS-MAC Software Exchange Library (Boston Computer Society Macintosh User Group), 1992 (Box 10)
- Bits & Bytes (Apple Computer Enjoyment Society, South Florida), 1981-1986 (Box 10)
- BMUG Newsletter (Berkeley Macintosh Users Group), 1985-1992 (Box 10, Box 11)
- C2MUG Bulletin (Command & Control Department of the U.S. Army Microcomputer Users Group), 1984-19989 (Box 11)
- Call - A.P.P.L.E. (Apple PugetSound Program Library Exchange) [see Mac A.P.P.L.E.], 1978-1990 (Box 11, Box 12)
- Call - A.P.P.L.E. In Depth (Apple PugetSound Program Library Exchange), 1981-1982 (Box 12)
- Candy Apple (South Jersey Apple/Mac Users Group, formerly New Jersey Apple Users Group), 1983-1996 (Box 12)
- Chips (Navy Regional Data Automation Center), 1986, 1988 (Box 12)
- C.I.A. Informer (Central Illinois Apple Users Group), 1984-1987 (Box 12)
- The Cider Press (Apple Computer Information & Data Exchange of Rochester, New York), 1980-1986 (Box 12)
- Cider Press (Apple Core Bay Area Mac Forum), 1978-1988 (Box 13, Box 12)
- Crystal Lake Apple News / CLAN (Apple People Computer Users Group, Illinois), 1988-1991 (Box 13)
- ClarisWorks Journal (ClarisWorks Users Group), 1992-1998 (Box 13)
- Club Mac of Monterey Journal (Club Mac of Monterey, California), 1986-1995 (Box 13)
- The Club Mac News (National Macintosh User Group), 1985-1986 (Box 13)
- CMAC Plus One (Club Mac of Toronto), 1987-1988 (Box 13)
- Communal Computing News (Communal Computing Group), 1989 (Box 13)
- CompuNik (Northweast Apple Pickers, Tacoma, Washington), 1986-1998 (Box 13)
- CompuShare (Bothell, Washington), 1988-1989 (Box 13)
- Computer Club News (Apple Computer Clubs International), 1985-1986 (Box 14)
- Computer Quarterly (Connecticut Computer Society, Inc.) [see Connecticut Computer News], 1991-1994 (Box 14)
- Computer Update (Boston Computer Society), 1981-1987 (Box 14)
- Computing in Russian, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
- Connecticut Computer News (Connecticut Computer Society, Inc.) [see Computer Quarterly], 1988-1991 (Box 14)
- Co-Op Spirit (TechAlliance Computer Co-Operative), 1991-1993 (Box 14)
- Crab-Apple Bulletin (County of Rockland Apple Branch, New York), 1982-1984 (Box 14)
- The CrabApple (Annapolis Apple Slice Computer Users Group, Maryland), 1989-1994 (Box 14)
- CSRA Computer Society, Inc. Newsletter (Augusta, Georgia), 1983-1988 (Box 14)
- D.C. Literacy Newsletter (D.C. Literacy Resource Center, Washington, D.C.), 1995-1997 (Box 14)
- Dental Computer Newsletter (Andent, Inc., Waukegan, Illinois), 1983-1991 (Box 14)
- The DeskTop Journal (Yale Macintosh Users' Group), 1985-1989 (Box 14)
- The Dialog Box (Sarasota/Manatee Macintosh Users Group, Florida), 1988-1994 (Box 14)
- EAC Express (Erie Apple Crunchers, Pennsylvania), 1982-1997 (Box 14)
- L'Echo des Apple (Club Apple, Paris, France), 1985 (Box 14)
- FACsheet (Flint Apple Club of Michigan), 1996 (Box 15)
- FATbits (CVMUG, Conejo Valley Macintosh Users Group, Thousand Oaks, California), 1985-1998 (Box 15)
- The Finder (Palmetto MacFinders, Charleston, South Carolina), 1993-1994 (Box 15)
- Fishwrap (AMUG, Atlanta Macintosh Users Group, Georgia), 1993-1997 (Box 15)
- FORTH Dimensions, MacForth, etc. (FORTH Interest Group, Potomac, Maryland), 1981-1984 (Box 15)
- Frederick Apple Core News (Frederick Slice of Washington Apple Pi / Frederick Apple Core), 1987-1991 (Box 15)
- From the Core (Carolina Apple Core User Group, Raleigh, North Carolina), 1980-1997 (Box 15, Box 16)
- Full Disclosure (MacWorld), 1991 (Box 16)
- The FWBAC News (Fort Walton Apple Club, Florida), 1988-1991 (Box 16)
- Get Info (MACS, Macintosh Asheville Computer Society, North Carolina), 1995-1998 (Box 16)
- GRAPEvine (Great Apple Program Exchange, Delaware & New Jersey), 1980-1989 (Box 16)
- GRApple News (Grand Rapids Apple II Users, Michigan), 1984-1988 (Box 16)
- Gravenstein / GSAUG (Gravenstein Apple Users Group, Petaluma, California), 1992-1998 (Box 16)
- GS+ (Chattanooga, Tennessee), 1989-1995 (Box 32)
- The Harvest (Northern Illinois Apple Users Group / Northern Illinois Computer Society / Northwest Suburban Apple Users Group), 1980-1989 (Box 16, Box 17)
- Icon / The Icon (Association of Apple 32 Users, Santa Clara, California), 1984-1997 (Box 17)
- Incider / PIE Incider (Programming & Interfacing Enthusiasts, Inc., Santa Clara, California), 1983-1998 (Box 17)
- Inside Apple (Charlotte Apple Computer Club, North Carolina), 1986-1994 (Box 17)
- Inside Hypercard (Cobb Group), 1991-1993 (Box 17)
- Inside Microsoft Works (Cobb Group), 1990-1992 (Box 17)
- Interface (MaxNexus, Sacramento Macintosh User Group) [see Interface], 1989-1998 (Box 17, Box 18)
- KAUG NewsBytes (Kokomo Apple Users Group, Indiana), 1988-1994 (Box 18)
- Keystone Apple Core (Pennsylvania), 1980-1983 (Box 18)
- Known Users (Sequoia Macintosh Users' Group, Arcata, California), 1985-1990 (Box 18)
- LAUGHS (Lousiville Apple Users Group, Kentucky), 1985-1986 (Box 18)
- Mac 2 News (Mac 2 Macintosh Users Group, Canton, Ohio), 1990-1991 (Box 18)
- Mac A.P.P.L.E. (Apple PugetSound Program Library Exchange) [see Call APPLE], 1987 (Box 18)
- MacCore (Kansas City Macintosh Computer Owners' Resource Exchange), 1988-1994 (Box 18)
- MacDigest (Los Angeles Macintosh Group, California), 1985-1990 (Box 18)
- Macintalk (MacInteresteds, Nashville, Tennessee), 1988-1997 (Box 18)
- Macintouch (San Diego Macintosh Users Group, California), 1993-1994 (Box 19)
- MacManiac (Macintosh Users Group of the Inland Empire, California), 1985-1986 (Box 19)
- MacNews (Eugene Macintosh Users' Group, Oregon), 1984-1998 (Box 19)
- MacNexus (Sacramento Macintosh Users' Group) [see Interface] (Box 19)
- Mac Notes (Aesis Development), 1985 (Box 19)
- The Mac Packer (The Dallas Mac Pack, Texas), 1986-1990 (Box 19)
- Mac Point (Dru Shipman, Chicago, Illinois), 1985 (Box 19)
- Mac's Headroom (Ft. Leavenworth Macintosh Users Group, Kansas), 1987-1989 (Box 20)
- Mac Street Journal (New York Mac Users' Group), 1984-1996 (Box 20)
- The Mac Times UK (Macintosh Users Group UK), 1987-1992 (Box 20)
- The Macvalley Voice (Macvalley Users Group, Burbank, California), 1985-1989 (Box 20)
- MacVIEWS (Professional Macintosh Users Group of Northeastern Indiana), 1993-1994 (Box 20)
- Mac Visions (Hawaii Macintosh Users Group) (Box 20)
- Mac West (Mac West Computer Society, British Columbia, Canada), 1996-1998 (Box 20)
- The Mad Mac News (Madison Macintosh Users Group, Wisconsin), 1986-1989 (Box 20)
- Magis ka Bladet (Stockholm, Sweden), 1985-1986 (Box 21)
- Maple Orchard (LOGIC Computer User Group, formerly Apple User Group of Toronto, Ontario, Canada), 1982-1994 (Box 21)
- Mini App'les Newsletter (Minnesota Apple Computer Users' Group), 1982-1998 (Box 21)
- Monitor (Capitol PC Users Group, Rockville, Maryland), 1993-1998 (Box 22)
- MOPMUG News (Monmouth Ocean Professionals Macintosh User Group, New Jersey), 1990-1992 (Box 22)
- Most Significant Bite (Applejacks of St. Louis, Missouri), 1982-1989 (Box 22)
- Mouse Droppings (Corvallis Macintosh Users Group, Oregon), 1985-1997 (Box 22)
- Mouse Tales (Mac-in-Awe MUG Computer Club, Michigan), 1988-1990 (Box 23)
- Mouse Times (Santa Barbara Macintosh Users Group, California), 1994-1997 (Box 23)
- Mouse Tracks (Sierra Nevada Apple Users Group, Nevada), 1993-1996 (Box 23)
- Mouse Tracks (Portland Macintosh Users Group, Oregon), 1985-1994 (Box 23)
- Mouse Tracks (Macintosh Enthusiasts of San Antonio, Texas), 1988-1990 (Box 23)
- Mugoo (Macintosh Users Group of Orlando, Florida), 1995 (Box 23)
- MUseletter (Columbia, Missouri Macintosh Users Group), 1987-1994 (Box 23)
- NCMC Bulletin / NCMC Update (National Capitol Macintosh Club, Ottawa, Canada), 1990-1996 (Box 23, Box 24)
- NEAT Notes (New England Apple Tree, Woburn, Massachusetts), 1980-1998 (Box 24)
- NEUMac News (North Eastern Users of the Macintosh, Albany, New York), 1987-1994 (Box 24)
- NHMUG News (NASA Headquarters Macintosh Users Group), 1989-1992 (Box 24)
- North West Passages (The Northwest of U.S. Macintosh Users' Group, Chicago, Illinois), 1994-1996 (Box 24)
- Novapple Newsletter (Northern Virginia Apple Users Group, Falls Church, Virginia), 1982-1997 (Box 24)
- NYMUG News (New York Mac Users' Group), 1990-1998 (Box 24)
- The OMNIS Connection (Blyth Software), 1986-1987 (Box 24)
- OMUG News (Omaha Macintosh Users Group, Nebraska), 1992-1996 (Box 25)
- On Three (On 3, Inc.), 1990-1991 (Box 25)
- Open Apple Gazette (Original Apple IIIrs, San Francisco, California), 1982-1984 (Box 25)
- Open-Apple (Tom Weishaar, Overland Park, Kansas), 1987-1988 (Box 25)
- Output / The Plane Apple Output (Plane Apple Users' Group, Wichita, Kansas), 1990-1993 (Box 25)
- The Panda (Pensacola Apple II User Group), 1993 (Box 25)
- Panhandler (Panhandle Macintosh User Group), 1994-1998 (Box 25)
- Pascal News (Pascal Users Group, Allentown, Pennsylvania), 1980-1981 (Box 25)
- PBCUG Communicator (Pemi-Baker Computer Users Group, Plymouth, New Hampshire), 1988-1992 (Box 25)
- The Peel (Birmingham Apple Core, Alabama) [see Apple Peel] (Box 25)
- Penn Printout (University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia), 1985-1994 (Box 25)
- Pentagon Macintosh Users Group News (Washington, D.C.), 1989-1993 (Box 25)
- PICA / IO (Public Interest Computer Association), 1986-1991 (Box 25)
- Pig Tales (Houston Area Apple User's Group, Texas), 1992-1996 (Box 25)
- PMUG Dialog / PMUG Newsletter (Princeton Macintosh User's Group, New Jersey), 1989-1996 (Box 25)
- Post Event / The Macadamian (Macadamia Macintosh Users' Group, Illinois), 1989-1995 (Box 25)
- Power Signal (Hawaii Macintosh & Apple Users' Society), 1994 (Box 25)
- Query (Syllabus Press, Sunnyvale, California), 1992-1994 (Box 25)
- QuickConnect (User Group Connection, Cupertino, California), 1986-1997 (Box 25)
- The Rag Times (Rhode Island Apple Group), 1987-1989 (Box 26)
- The Rainbow (Aresco, Inc., Columbia, Maryland), 1979 (Box 26)
- RAMblings (Worcester Computer Society), 1990-1994 (Box 26)
- Random Access (University of Texas Macintosh Users Group, Austin), 1985-1990 (Box 26)
- Read Me/ NOMUG (New Orleans Macintosh Users' Group, Metaire, Louisiana), 1985-1993 (Box 26)
- Resources / San Diego Mac News (San Diego Macintosh Users Group), 1984-1993 (Box 26)
- The Rest of Us (Chicago Area Macintosh Users' Group, Illinois), 1985-1989 (Box 27)
- The RIAG Times / The RIAG (Rhode Island Apple Group), 1991-1997 (Box 27)
- SCAN (Suncoast Apple Tree Users Group, Clearwater, Florida), 1980-1993 (Box 27)
- The Scarlett Letter / Scarlett (Big Red Computer Club, Norfolk, Nebraska), 1983-1994 (Box 27)
- The Seed (Denver Apple Pi, Colorado), 1980-1998 (Box 27)
- Seeds & Stems / Seeds n' Stems (Maryland Apple Corps), 1984-1988 (Box 27)
- Signal / Apple Signal (Hawaii Macintosh & Apple Users' Society, merged with Honolulu Apple Users Society in 1993), 1986-1998 (Box 28)
- Smalltalk / V Scoop (Digitalk, Inc.), 1989-1991 (Box 28)
- SMC Newsletter (Syracuse Microcomputer Club, New York), 1984-1986 (Box 28)
- SMUG News (Stanford/Palo Alto Computer User Group, California), 1985-1998 (Box 28)
- SNAC Time (Southern New Hampshire Apple Core), 1981-1998 (Box 28)
- SPA News (Software Publishers Association), 1992-1994 (Box 28)
- SWACKS (SWACKS Apple Computer Club, North Fort Myers, Florida), 1992-1993 (Box 28)
- Syllabus / Computer Science Syllabus (Box 29)
- TART (The Apple Resource Team, Richmond, Virginia), 1979-1985 (Box 29)
- TASIE News (The Apple Southeastern Information Exchange, Wilmington, North Carolina), 1987-1988 (Box 29)
- TAU Tales (TAU-RJW Phase III, Wheaton, Illinois), 1984-1987 (Box 29)
- That Computes! (Catawba Valley Byte 32 Mac Users' Group, Hickory, North Carolina), 1990-1991 (Box 29)
- Toledo Apple Users Newsletter (Ohio), 1989-1991 (Box 29)
- Townesville Apple Group Newsletter (North Queensland, Australia), 1988-1992 (Box 29)
- Upstate Apple Users Group News (New Hartford, New York), 1981-1988 (Box 29)
- User Magazin (AUGE, Hamburg, Germany), 1989, 1991 (Box 29)
- USUS Newsletter (UCSD Pascal System Users' Society, La Jolla, California), 1989-1992 (Box 29)
- VMUG Voice (Virginia Macintosh Users Group), 1992-1996 (Box 29)
- Windows (Mac Orange User Group, Huntington Beach, California), 1985-1986 (Box 29)
- Worm Words (Tidewater Apple Worms, Virginia Beach, Virginia), 1982-1993 (Box 29)
- miscellaneous newsletters (groups represented by one issue only) (Box 29)
- Washington Apple Pi (Washington, D.C.), 1980-1999
  - Washington Apple Pi (Washington, D.C.) vol.2 no.7 7/1980 - vol.10 no.6 6/1988, 1980-1988 (Box 30)
  - Washington Apple Pi (Washington, D.C.) vol.10 no.7 7/1988 - vol.15 no.12 12/1993, 1988-1993 (Box 31)
  - Washington Apple Pi (Washington, D.C.) vol.16 no.1 1/1994 - vol.16 no.3 5-6/1999, 1994-1999 (Box 32)
  - Washington Apple Pi (Washington, D. C.) [vol. 2 no.1 1/1980] - vol. 2 no.6 6/1980 (Half-box 33, Folder 2)
  - Inside Washington Apple Pi (Half-box 33, Folder 1)